<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: College | Pronoy Chopra's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://DarkSector.github.com/blog/categories/college/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://DarkSector.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-21T18:50:45+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://DarkSector.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pronoy Chopra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transcripts]]></title>
    <link href="http://DarkSector.github.com/blog/transcripts/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T16:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://DarkSector.github.com/blog/transcripts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, it turns out, applying to universities abroad isn't that easy. The worse part is they are arrogant enough to not inform you, that your documents are incomplete. I had to call the universities to check if everything was alright and they replied in the negative. I panicked and called all my relatives who knew about sending documents to the US.</p>

<p>The transcripts that need to be sent to the US should be sealed and sent directly by your previous university. I contacted my counsellor at Jamboree and she said it was obvious. Apparently it isn't obvious. On that note, if you're thinking of trying for the US and are thinking of seeking help for the same then please keep the next few lines in mind:</p>

<h5>Jamboree is a unit of incredibly incompetent individuals who are not only unable to bring about a credible result but are also very inept at training the students for GRE or TOEFL. I took my exam after having prepared with them and scored a dismal 1190. I retook the test on my own and got a 314 without anyone's help. As far as admissions are concerned Jamboree is just one of those faces in a dingy street that promise results without actually ever delivering them. They are callous and misinformed.</h5>

<p>That being said, lets move on. The universities require sealed transcripts which in my case had to be retrieved by visiting my undergrad university in person and obtaining them. Oh god, I hate that place. But I got through. Then I got my individual mark sheets attested by a notary. That cost me a lot. I mean every document costs about 150 INR to be validated and I had 20 copies to be validated. After having validated them, I sent them flying to the respective destinations via FedEX.</p>

<p>What a pain it has been.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
